（纽约市）
这个未来
The future.
一个阴暗凄凉的世界
A dark, desolate world.
充满战争 痛苦 失去的世界
A world of war, suffering, loss…
两边都一样
on both sides.
变种人和大胆帮助他们的人类
Mutants and the humans who dared to help them.
对抗一个我们无法击败的敌人
Fighting an enemy we cannot defeat.
我们是注定走上这条路的吗？
Are we destined down this path?
和过去那些物种一样注定自我毁灭？
Destined to destroy ourselves like so many species before us?
还是我们能快速演化 改变自己
Or can we evolve fast enough to change ourselves?
扭转我们的命运？
Change our fate?
未来真的已成定论了吗？
Is the future truly set?
《X战警：逆转未来》
（莫斯科）
它们来了
They're here!
没时间了
Time's up.
哨兵机器人
Sentinels!
太阳黑子
Sunspot!
我们走
Let's go.
快跑
Run!
去吧
Go!
闪烁 不要啊
Blink! No!
太晚了 混蛋
Too late, assholes.
别跑 你这变种杂碎
Don't move, you mutant scum!
不要
No!
趴下 手放在头后面
Flat on the ground, hands behind your head!
我们只剩下几个人
So few ofus left.
教授？
Professor?
找到他们了
I've found them.
（中国）
教授
Professor!
- 冰人 - 嘿 暴风女
- Bobby. - Hey, Storm.
小子
Hey, kid.
教授 你来了
Professor, you made it.
哨兵一攻击 战迹就会找到它们
Whenever the Sentinels attack, Warpath spots them…
然后我派主教回去 提前警告我们
then I send Bishop back to warn us of the attack before it happens.
闪烁在下一个地点勘查
Blink scouts the next site…
我们会在它们发现前离开
and then we leave before they ever know we were there.
因为我们从没出现过
Because… we never were.
这是什么意思？
What do you mean you were never there?
她把主教送回几天前去警告其他人
She projects Bishop back in time a few days to warn the others…
提防下次的攻击
of the coming attack.
她把主教送回过去？
So she sends Bishop back in time?
不 回去的只有他的意识
No, just his consciousness, into his younger self.
回到他年轻的身体里
His younger body.
真厉害
Wow.
说不定这样有用 查尔斯
This might just work, Charles.
什么有用？
What might work?
哨兵计划是波利瓦崔斯克博士提出的
The Sentinel Program was originally conceived by Doctor Bolivar Trask.
他是70年代初顶尖的武器设计者
In the early '70s, he was one of the world's leading weapons designers.
但他偷偷开始用变种人做实验
But, covertly, he had begun experimenting on mutants…
利用他们的能力做研究
using their gifts to fuel his own research.
这太特别了
This is extraordinary.
有一个变种人发现他的计划
There was one mutant who had discovered what he was doing.
而这个变种人的能力是改变外型
A mutant with the ability to transform herself into anyone.
魔形女
Mystique.
我叫她瑞雯
I knew her as Raven.
我们从小一起长大
We met when we were children, grew up together.
她就像我的妹妹
She was like a sister to me.
我试着帮她
I tried to help her…
但反而让她离我远去
but only succeeded in driving her away.
她跑遍世界追杀崔斯克
She hunted Trask across the world.
1973年越战结束签暑巴黎和平条约时
And at the Paris Peace Accords in 1973, after the Vietnam War…
她找到了崔斯克
she found Trask…
然后杀了他
and killed him.
那是她第一次杀人
It was the first time she killed.
但不是最后一次
It wasn't her last.
但崔斯克死后的结果并不如她所愿
But killing Trask did not have the outcome she expected.
反而让政府相信他的计划是必要的
It only persuaded the government of the need for his program.
他们当天就抓到她
They captured her that day…
折磨她 用她做实验
tortured her, experimented on her.
政府在她的DNA里发现她变形的秘密
In her DNA, they discovered the secrets to herpowers of transformation.
他们因此获得关键能力
It gave them the key they needed…
制造出能适应所有变种能力的武器
to create weapons that could adapt to any mutant power
不到50年
And in less than 50 years…
他们就完成了这种机器
the machines that have destroyed…
杀死了无数的变种人同胞
so many of our kind were created.
但一切都是从1973年的那天开始
But it all started that day in 1973…
她第一次杀人的那天
the day she first killed.
她在那一天才真正…
The day she truly became…
成为魔形女
Mystique.
你想回到当时
You want to go back there.
如果我能阻止她杀人
If I can get to her, stop the assassination…
保护她不被抓住
keep her out of their hands…
我们就能阻止哨兵机器人的诞生
then we can stop the Sentinels from ever being born.
在这场战争开始前就结束它
And end this war before it ever begins.
我可以把人送回去几周前
I can send someone back a couple weeks.
最多一个月
Maybe a month.
但你要让人回到几十年前
But you're talking about going back decades.
虽然你有全世界最强大的头脑
You have the most powertul brain in the world, Professor…
但是心智的承受能力是有极限的
but the mind can only stretch so far before it snaps.
这么做会杀了你 抱歉
It would rip you apart. I'm sorry.
没有人能撑过这趟时空之旅
No one could survive that trip.
如果那个人的心智能恢复呢？
What if someone's mind has a way of snapping back?
如果那个人一受伤就能马上复原呢？
What if someone can heal as fast as they're ripped apart?
这是个风险
It's a risk.
好 我了解
Yeah, I'm getting that.
不只是你
Not just for you.
你完成这个 你就会改变历史
You do this, you change history.
这是重点
That's kind of the point.
我们其中有人可能会死
Some of us could be killed.
有些可能从未出生过 我们不知道会有什么改变
Some of us may never be born. We have no idea how things may change.
我们能继续前进
We could keep going.
持续抗战
Keep fighting.
直到什么？
Until what?
你们要下决定
You've got a decision to make.
你们可以把主教送回过去 一再一再地警告你们
You can keep sending Bishop back in time over and over again to warn you,
直到有一天 他做不到 你们所有人都会死
until one day, he doesn't make it, and you all die.
或者你们能放弃这一生
Or you can give up this life.
所以他们还有其余死于这战争的人
So that they and everyone else who died in this war
能有未来
can actually have a future.
你要求我们为了可能不会拥有的未来 牺牲自己的性命
You're asking us to sacrifice our lives for a future we might not even be a part of.
对
Yes.
第二次机会
A second chance.
对大家来说更好的机会
A better chance for everyone.
我们必须表决
My people need to vote.
他们刚刚决定了
They just did.
他们愿意
They're in.
好 散开
Okay, spread out.
各就各位
Take your positions.
我会在某处我年轻的身体中苏醒
So I wake up in my younger body, God knows where.
然后呢？
Then what?
你得去我家找我
You'll need to go to my house and find me.
说服我相信这一切
Convince me of all of this.
你不是能读我的心吗？
Won't you be able to just read my mind?
我在1973年没这个能力
I didn't have my powers in 1973.
罗根 你要做的正是我曾为你做的
Logan, you're going to have to do for me what I once did for you.
带领我 引导我
Lead me, guide me.
我那时候和现在很不一样
I was a very different man then.
你要对我有点耐心
You'll have to be patient with me.
我超有耐心的
Patience is my strongest suit.
- 你也会需要我 - 什么？
- You'll need me as well. - What?
魔形女离开查尔斯之后跟我走了
After Mystique left Charles, she came with me…
我让她走上那条危险的道路
and I set her on a dangerous path.
黑暗的道路
A darker path.
我们需要一起合作
It's going to take the two of us, side by side…
在一个我们水火不容的年代
at a time when we couldn't be further apart.
真是太好了
Great.
我要去哪里找你？
So where do I find you?
嗯 有点复杂
Well, it's complicated.
你确定吗？
Are you sure about this?
这不只测试他的能力 我也看过这对你的影响
It's not just his power that'll be tested. I've seen what this can do to you.
我可以应付的
I can handle this.
相信我
Trust me.
我想我们在来生见了
I guess I'll see you in the next life.
你的精神回到过去时 身体会睡着
Basically, your body will go to sleep while your mind travels back in time.
你一回去 现在和过去会并存
As long as you're back there, past and present will continue to coexist.
等到你一醒来
But once you wake up…
你做过的事就会成为确定的历史
whatever you've done will take hold and become history.
我们其他人也只会知道那段历史
And for the rest of us, it will be the only history that we know.
过去50年的事就像从没发生过
It will be like the last 50 years never happened.
这个世界 这场战争
And this world, and this war…
唯一记得一切的只有你
the only person who will remember it is you.
好 罗根
All right, Logan…
我要你放空 尽量保持冷静
I need you to clear your head and to stay as calm as possible.
为什么？
What? What do you mean?
如果你情绪激动我就抓不到你
If your mind gets rocky, it will be harder for me to hold you…
你可能会迷失在过去与现在之间
and you could start to slip between past and future.
如果我不得不有情绪呢？
What if I need to get a little rocky?
试试平静的想法？
Think peaceful thoughts?
说得简单… 来点好消息吧
Peaceful thoughts… Do you have any good news?
你不会老 所以你的外表是一样的
Well, you don't really age, so you'll pretty much look the same.
你在过去不会有很多时间
You won't have much time in the past.
哨兵会找到我们
The Sentinels will find us.
它们总是能找到我们
They always do.
而且这次我们不能跑了
And this time, we won't be able to run.
我们无处可逃
We'll have no escape.
这是最后一搏了
This is our last chance.
- 你觉得会成功吗？- 我相信他
- You really think this will work? - I have faith in him.
我担心的不是他 是我们
It's not him I'm worried about, it's us.
我们那时还年轻
We were young…
什么都还不懂
we didn't know any better.
这次我们会懂的
We will now.
待会儿见了
See you all soon.
可能会有一点痛
This might sting a little.
我的老天
Holy shit.
居然成功了
It worked.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
- 葛玟 穿上衣服 - 你到底是谁？
- Gwen, get dressed. - Who the hell are you?
我不知道怎么回事
I don't know what's going on.
你应该保护老板的女儿 不是上她
You're supposed to be guarding the boss's daughter, not screwing her.
我没有跟她上床
Well, I didn't sleep with her.
- 没有吗？- 没有
- No? - No.
其实我上过很多次了
I mean, yes, I slept with her many times.
吉米
Jimmy!
但是那不是我 是过去的我
That wasn't me. That was the old me.
我才刚到这里
I just got here 20 seconds ago.
是吗？那你的衣服呢？
Really? Then what happened to your clothes?
我的… 喔
My…
你相信我来自未来吗？
Would you believe me if I told you I was sent here from the future?
- 出去 亲爱的 - 也好
- Get out of here, sweetheart. - Yeah.
- 我们会料理这个小丑 - 你们不会
- We're gonna take care of this comedian. - No, you're not.
你要给我车钥匙还有加油的钱
You're gonna give me the keys to your car and some money for gas…
不然就会在医院醒来
or you're gonna wake up in the hospital.
相信我 我知道结果会怎样
Trust me, I know how these things play out.
因为你来自未来吗？
Because you're from the future?
不
No.
因为我有这个
Because of these.
什么鬼东西
What the hell?
该死的
God damn it!
平静的想法
Peaceful thoughts.
（幸运星）
吉米 罗曼怎么了？
Jimmy! What happened to Ramon?
你在说什么啊？
And why are you talking crazy talk?
- 听好 - 葛玟
- Look… - Gwen.
葛玟 你要低调几天？好吗 从现在开始
Gwen, you're gonna wanna lay low for a few days, all right? Starting now.
快点 出来
Come on, out.
快走
Go.
今天 第18宪兵队从西贡出发
Today the 18th MP Brigade is departing from Saigon,
这是最后一批离开越南的美军
marking the last American troops to leave Vietnam.
表示战争的结束
And effectively ending the war
我们正在审查国防费用
We are reviewing all of our defense expenditures…
连机密计划也不例外
and all the black books are being opened.
我们不能支持攻击人民的武器
We can't support a weapon that targets our own citizens.
如果这些变种人像你说的
If these mutants, as you describe…
已经在我们周遭生活
are already living among us…
那他们也没有惹是生非
then they are living here peacefully.
过去10年都没出过问题
We haven't had an incident in over 10 years.
古巴那件事不算吗？
After what happened in Cuba?
这事没有证据
That was never confirmed.
现在我们真正的敌人
We have very real enemies out there…
是苏俄 中国
the Russians, the Chinese.
变种人占总人口的比例
We are talking about a tenth of a tenth…
小得不能再小
of a tenth of our population.
请听我念一段文字
Allow me to read something to you.
请念
Please.
我要念的内容来自中情局
This was acquired by our friends at the CIA.
是一份论文
It's a dissertation…
作者是牛津大学的变种人
written by a mutant at Oxford University.
我引述内容如下
And I quote…
「对尼安德塔人而言
"To Homo Neanderthalensis…
他的突变近亲「智人」…
his mutant cousin, Homo Sapiens…"
也就是我们
Which is us…
「是畸形的…
"was an aberration.
变种的“智人”一出现
The arrival of the mutated human species, Homo Sapiens…
他们的劣等近亲就马上灭亡「
was followed by the immediate extinction of their less evolved kin."
现在我们就是那些尼安德塔人
Now, we are the Neanderthal.
你说的是自己吧 崔斯克博士
Speak for yourself, Dr. Trask.
当你们把我们的子弟送去越南
You know, when you sent our soldiers to Vietnam…
但没有给他们没有打胜仗的武器时
without the weapons they needed to win the war…
你们低估了敌人
you underestimated your enemy.
如果你们也小看这种敌人
You do that with this enemy…
就再也不会只是遥远的土地之争
and it won't be some border skirmish haltway around the world.
这一次 战争会在我们的街头发生
This time, the war will be for our streets…
在我们的城市 家里
our cities, our homes…
到你们需要我的计划时
and by the time you see the need for my program…
已经来不及了
it will be too late…
你们一生中会吃下两场败仗
and you will have lost two wars in one lifetime.
抱歉 崔斯克博士
We are sorry, Dr. Trask…
但你的哨兵机器人计划
but your Sentinel Program…
不会成真
it ain't gonna fly.
（西贡）
有什么事吗 上校？
Can I help you, Colonel?
只是来向这些孩子道别
Just here to give our boys a proper send-off.
抱歉长官 按规定这里是隔离区
I'm sorry, sir, but we have orders. This is a quarantined area.
让开 士兵
Stand aside, soldier.
这是命令
That's an order.
注意
Atten-hut!
稍息
At ease.
这些是什么？
What is all this?
实验室报告 血液测试
Lab reports, blood tests.
全部要打包运回去
It's all getting packed up and shipped back.
运到哪里？
Where is it going?
跟他们同一个地方
Same place they are.
崔斯克企业
Trask Industries.
（机密 崔斯克医疗与血液检验报告）
走吧 各位
Let's go, gentlemen.
我带你们离开这场闹剧
I'm taking you out of this shit show.
要回家了吗？
Shipping home?
还没
Not just yet.
这些是干嘛的？
What are you doing with those?
让你们旅程更舒服用的
Something to make the ride a little smoother.
你们会被送到私人机构
I'm transferring you to a private facility…
进行更多测试
where we can run a few more tests.
你们不是军方
Your men are not military.
我们是私人单位
Private outfit.
但有权处置他们
We're authorized to remand these men.
这些军人要回家
These troops are going home.
上校 我想你没有权力管这件事
Well, Colonel, I don't believe you have jurisdiction in this matter.
我想我有的 孩子
I'm afraid I do, son.
抱歉 你是谁？
I'm sorry, who are you?
问题是 少校…
The question is, Major…
（小威廉史崔克）
你又是谁？
who are you?
瑞雯
Raven!
那不是我的名字
That's not my name.
我不用帮手
I had that.
我知道
I know.
我们走吧 快走
Let's move out. Come on, let's go.
艾瑞克呢？
Where's Erik?
我现在靠自己
I'm on my own now.
快走 动作快
Let's go! Move it!
阻止那架飞机
Hold that plane!
我们可不想让孩子们留在这鬼地方
Wouldn't wanna leave these boys in this godforsaken country.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
你不跟我们走？
You're not coming with us, are you?
我的战争还没结束
My war's not over.
敌人还没消灭
The enemy is still out there.
那四个士兵去哪了？
The four privates, where did they go?
他们去停机坪那边了
They were headed towards the tarmac.
（私人财产 禁止进入）
（X教授资优青少年学校）
有事吗？
Can I help you?
这间学校怎么了？
Yeah, what happened to the school?
学校很多年前就关了 你是家长？
The school's been shut for years. Are you a parent?
我希望千万不是 你是谁？
I sure as hell hope not. Who are you?
我是汉克 汉克麦考伊
I'm Hank. Hank McCoy.
这里现在是我在照顾
I look after the house now.
你是野兽？
You're Beast?
瞧瞧你 肯定是大器晚成
Look at you. I guess you're a late bloomer.
我不知道你在说什么 但请离开
I don't know what you're talking about, but I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
教授在哪？
So where's the Professor?
这里没有教授
There's no professor here.
以一个骨瘦如柴的孩子来说你算强壮
You're pretty strong for a scrawny kid.
你确定这里没有一只小野兽？
You sure there's not a little Beast in there?
- 没有 - 少来了 野兽
- No, he's not here. - Come on, Beast.
- 别装了 野兽 - 没有
- Come on, Beastie. - No.
我说过学校关闭了
I said the school's closed.
- 你得离开 - 除非我见到教授
- You need to leave. - Not until I see the Professor.
我说过这里没有教授
There's no professor here, I told you that.
听着 我们以后会是好朋友
Look, kid. You and I are gonna be good friends.
你只是还不知道
You just don't know it yet.
教授
Professor!
汉克？
Hank?
怎么回事？
What's going on here?
教授？
Professor?
请别这样叫我
Please don't call me that.
为什么？你认识这家伙？
Why? You know this guy?
他看起来是有点面熟
Yeah, he looks slightly familiar.
从那鬼吊灯上下来吧 汉克
Get off the bloody chandelier, Hank.
你居然能走路
You can walk.
你观察力不错
You're a perceptive one.
艾瑞克不是…
I thought Erik…
那你怎么会没看到我们的标示？
Which makes it slightly perplexing that you missed our sign on the way in.
这里是私人财产 朋友
This is private property, my friend.
我必须请你离开
I'm gonna have to ask him to ask you to leave.
恐怕我做不到
I'm afraid I can't do that…
因为我是被派来找你的
because I was sent here for you.
去告诉派你来的人 我很忙
Tell whoever it was that sent you that I'm busy.
这挺麻烦的
That's gonna be a little tricky…
因为派我来的人是你
because the person who sent me was you.
什么？
What?
是大约50年后的你
About 50 years from now.
我知道 请听我说
I know. Stay with me.
- 你是说50年后的未来？- 对
- Like in the future, 50 years from now? - Yeah.
- 我从未来派你过来？- 对
- I sent you from the future? - Yeah.
滚吧
Piss off.
要是你现在有能力就会知道我没说谎
If you had your powers, you'd know I was telling the truth.
你怎么知道我没有…
How do you know I don't have my p…
- 你是谁？- 我说过了
- Who are you? - I told you.
- 中情局的？- 不是
- Are you CIA? - No.
你一直在监视我？
You've been watching me?
我认识你 查尔斯
I know you, Charles.
我们是很多年的朋友
We've been friends for years.
我知道你9岁开始有这能力
I know your powers came when you were 9.
我知道一开始你都要疯了
I know you thought you were going crazy when it started…
因为脑中出现那么多声音
all the voices in your head.
到你12岁的时候
And it wasn't until you were 12…
你才知道不是人人都会听到声音
that you realized all the voices were in everyone else's head.
你要我继续说吗？
Do you want me to go on?
我从没告诉过任何人
I never told anyone that.
还没有 但以后你会的
Not yet, no, but, you will.
你让我有点兴趣了 你想干嘛？
All right, you've piqued my interest. What do you want?
我们要阻止瑞雯
We have to stop Raven.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
我们需要你帮忙
We need your help.
我想结束这个梦了
I think I'd like to wake up now.
她跟这事有什么关系？
What does she have to do with this?
你是说…
So you're saying…
他们夺走了瑞雯的能力 然后？
they took Raven's power, and what?
把它变成一种武器？
They weaponized it?
对
Yep.
她很特别
She is unique.
的确 汉克
Yeah, she is, Hank.
一开始 哨兵只锁定变种人
In the beginning, the Sentinels were just targeting mutants.
后来他们开始检查非变种人的基因
Then they began to identity the genetics in non-mutants…
找出后代会出现变种人的人类
who would eventually have mutant children and grandchildren.
很多人类想帮我们 结果死伤惨重
Many of the humans tried to help us, but it was a slaughter.
存活下来的都是最邪恶的人类
Leaving only the worst of humanity in charge.
我经历过很多战争
I've been in a lot of wars.
从来没看过这么惨烈的
I'd never seen anything like this.
一切都是因她而起
And it all starts with her.
这么说好了 如果…
Let's just say for the sake of…
如果我真的选择相信你
the sake, that I choose to believe you…
就算我帮你 瑞雯也不会听我的
that I choose to help you. Raven won't listen to me.
她的心现在在另一个人身上
Her heart and soul belong to someone else now.
我知道
I know.
所以我们也需要万磁王
That's why we're gonna need Magneto, too.
艾瑞克？
Erik?
- 你知道他在哪里吗？- 知道
- You do know where he is? - Yeah.
请再说一次好吗？
Could you give me that one more time, please?
你听到我说的了
You heard me.
他在最适合他的地方
He's where he belongs.
你打算这样走掉？
You're just gonna walk out?
一百分 我就说你观察力很好
Top marks. Like I said, you are perceptive.
我认识的教授永远不会…
The Professor I know would never turn his back…
放弃任何迷失方向的人
on someone who'd lost their path.
特别不会放弃他爱的人
Especially someone he loved.
对了…
You know…
我想起来了
I think I do remember you now.
对 那发型奇怪 愤世嫉俗的高家伙
Yeah. Tall, angry fellow with the contentious hair.
我们很久以前见过 我去找你帮忙
We came to you a long time ago… seeking your help.
现在我要把你说过的话全数奉还
And I'm gonna say to you what you said to us then.
他妈的滚开
Fuck off.
你这个懦夫
Listen to me, you little shit.
我大老远跑来 看到那么多人死去
I've come a long way, and I've watched a lot of people die.
他们都是好人 是我的朋友
Good people. Friends.
要是你自怨自艾
If you're gonna wallow in self-pity…
不采取行动 悲剧就会重演
and do nothing, then you're gonna watch the same thing…
你懂不懂？
you understand?
人总会一死
We all have to die sometime.
跟你说过教授不在了
Told you there was no professor here.
他到底怎么了？
What the hell happened to him?
他失去了一切
He lost everything.
艾瑞克 瑞雯
Erik, Raven…
还有他的腿
his legs.
我们建立了学校 实验室 这地方
We built the school, the labs, this whole place…
结果第一个学期过后
then, just after the first semester…
因为越战情况恶化
the war in Vietnam got worse.
很多老师
Many of the teachers…
还有比较大的学生都被征召了
and older students were drafted.
他大受打击
It broke him.
一蹶不振
He retreated into himself.
我想帮忙做点什么
I wanted to help, do something…
所以我研发治疗他脊椎的血清
so I designed a serum to treat his spine…
基本配方和控制我能力的血清一样
derived from the same formula that helps me control my mutation.
我使用的量刚好能维持平衡
I take just enough to keep myself balanced…
但他用太多了
but he takes too much.
我试着让他戒掉
I tried easing him back…
但他受不了那些痛苦 那些声音
but he just couldn't bear the pain, the voices.
血清让他的腿恢复
The treatment gives him his legs…
但这样还不够
but it's not enough.
他失去太多了
He's just lost too much.
你不怕我？
You're not scared of me?
我一直相信我不会是孤独的
I always believed I couldn't be the only one in the world.
我是查尔斯赛维尔
Charles Xavier
我是瑞雯
Raven.
你饿了 而且很孤单
You're hungry and alone.
尽量拿吧 我们食物很多 不用偷
Take whatever you want. We've got lots of food. You don't have to steal.
我想
In fact…
你永远都不用再偷了
you never have to steal again.
这是我的承诺
And that's a promise.
我会帮你找到她
I'll help you get her.
不是为了什么鬼未来 是为了她
Not for any of your future shite, but for her.
没问题
Fair enough.
但我警告你 你不认识艾瑞克
But I'll tell you this. You don't know Erik.
他是怪物 是杀人犯
That man is a monster. A murderer.
你以为你能说服瑞雯回头？
You think you can convince Raven to change? To come home?
那可真了不起
That's splendid.
但你怎么会觉得自己能改变他？
But what makes you think you can change him?
因为是你和艾瑞克一起送我回来的
Because you and Erik sent me back here together.
他被关在二次大战盖的一个房间里
The room they're holding him in was built during the Second World War…
当时钢铁短缺
When there was a shortage of steel.
所以地基是混凝土和沙 没有金属
So the foundation is pure concrete and sand. No metal.
他被关在
He's being held…
他被关在世界上防守最严密的地方
a hundred floors beneath the most heavily guarded building on the planet.
为什么？
Why is he in there?
他忘记说了吗？
What, he forgot to mention?
甘迺迪
JFK.
是他？
He killed…
不然那颗子弹为什么会在空中转弯？
What else explains a bullet miraculously curving through the air?
艾瑞克很能控制武器
Erik's always had a way with guns.
你确定要继续吗？
Are you sure you want to carry on with this?
这是你的计划 不是我的
This is your plan, not mine.
我们没有闯进去的资源
We don't have any resources to get us in.
也没办法出来
Or out.
只有我和汉克
It's just me and Hank.
我认识一个人
I knew a guy.
他现在应该还年轻
Yeah, he'd be a young man now.
他在特区郊外长大
Grew up outside of D.C.
他无孔不入
He could get into anywhere.
但我不知道怎么找到他
I just don't know how the hell we're gonna find him.
脑波增幅器不能用？
Is Cerebro out of the question?
如果你们有网路
If only you guys had Internet.
什么是「网路」
What's "Internet?"
我们有电话簿
We have a phonebook.
（T崔斯克）
我以为您准备出发了
I thought you'd be getting ready for your trip, sir.
我只是回来拿点资料
I just came to grab a couple files.
新围巾吗？很漂亮
Is that a new scart? It's nice.
谢谢您
Thank you.
（武器测试）
（解剖报告）
崔斯克博士？
Dr. Trask?
等一下
One second.
我们在巴黎会议上加了几个人
We added some names to the Paris meeting.
谢谢你
Thank you.
怎么了吗 老板？
Is something wrong, sir?
没事
No. It's nothing.
请你帮我把行程打出来
Would you mind typing up my itinerary?
我不想有遗漏
I don't wanna miss anything.
- 这边这边 - 哪边？
- Here, here, here. - Where?
- 就停这里 - 好啦
- Just stop here. - All right, all right.
下次让我开 我好不习惯
Next time I'm driving. Don't get used to it.
（快银）
他这次又干嘛了？
What's he done now?
我会赔偿他拿走的东西
I will just write you a check for whatever he took.
我们只是想跟他聊聊
We just need to talk to him.
彼得 条子又来了
Peter! The cops are here. Again.
我是公主 你们是谁？
I'm a princess. What are you?
我是金钢狼
I'm the Wolverine.
你哥哥在哪？
Where's your brother?
到楼上烦你的姐姐
Go upstairs and bug your sister.
但她会烦我
But she bugs me!
你们这些人想干嘛？
What do you guys want?
我啥都没干 整天都在这里
I didn't do anything. I've been here all day.
放轻松 我们不是警察
Just relax, Peter. We're not cops.
当然不是 否则你们不会租车
Of course you're not. If you were, you wouldn't be driving a rental car.
你怎么知道我们的车是租的？
How did you know we've got a rental car?
你们进门的时候我查了车牌登记
I checked your registration when you were walking to the door.
还有时间看了一下你们的租约
I also had some time to kill so I went through your rental agreement.
你们不是这里的人 是FBI吗？
Saw you were from out of town. Are you FBI?
你们不是条子 是资优生学校的人？
No, you're not cops. What's with this gifted youngsters place?
这是旧的名片
That's an old card.
- 他很有趣 - 他是个捣蛋鬼
- He's fascinating. - He's a pain in the arse.
他会心电感应？
What, a teleporter?
不 只是动作快
No, he's just fast.
我认识的他没这么年轻
And when I knew him he wasn't so… young.
年轻？是你老吧
Young? You're just old.
你不怕展现能力？
So you're not afraid to show your powers?
什么能力？你在说什么？
What powers? What are you talking about?
你看到什么怪事吗？
Do you see something strange here?
反正说了也不会有人相信
Nothing anybody would believe if you told them.
你们是谁？想干嘛？
So, who are you? What do you want?
- 我们要你帮忙 彼得 - 做什么？
- We need your help, Peter. - For what?
闯入一个戒备森严的机构
To break into a highly secured facility…
把某人弄出来
and to get someone out.
越狱？
Prison break?
你们知道这是犯法的吧
That's illegal, you know.
被抓到才算犯法
Only if you get caught.
那我有什么好处？
So, what's in it for me?
你这个窃盗狂可以闯入五角大厦
You, you kleptomaniac, get to break into the Pentagon.
我怎么知道能信任你们？
How do I know I can trust you?
因为我们跟你一样
Because we're just like you.
让他瞧瞧
Show him.
很酷 不过挺恶心的
That's cool, but it's disgusting.
（国防部五角大厦）
五角大厦是全球最大的办公室
Built in 1943, the Pentagon is the world's largest office building…
建于1943年 有25 000多名军人
housing more than 25, 000 military employees…
办公面积超过600万平方尺
stretched over six million square feet.
厕所在哪里？
Where's the bathroom?
他老是想尿尿
He always needs to pee!
你很幸运 这里有很多厕所
Lucky for you, you'll have…
（禁止金属入内）
这里收到了电视画面 怎么回事？
We're getting broadcast signal down here. What's going on?
叫维修人员下来
Damn it, call Maintenance, get them down here.
（注意玻璃）
与日本在硫磺岛一战遭俘
Fought for and captured the island of Iwo Jima from the Japanese Empire.
这场战役长达一个月
Now, this month-long battle…
包含二战时在太平洋的几场激烈战役
included some of the fiercest fighting during World War II in the Pacific…
三秒后这扇门会打开
In three seconds, those doors are going to open…
会有20个警卫对我们开枪
and 20 guards will be here to shoot us.
我知道 我就在等这一刻
I know. That's what I'm waiting for.
你干嘛？
What are you doing?
抓住你的脖子你才不会扭伤
I'm holding your neck so you don't get whiplash.
什么？
What?
脖子扭伤
Whiplash.
不准动
Don't move!
等等就好了 每个人都会这样
You're good, it'll pass. It happens with everyone.
你一定干了什么坏事
You must have done something pretty serious.
你做了什么？
What did you do, man?
What did you do?
你做了什么？戒备这么森严？
What did you do? Why'd they have you in there?
我杀了总统
For killing the President.
我的妈呀
Wow. Shit.
我唯一的错是为了我们这种人而战
The only thing I'm guilty of is fighting for people like us.
你会跆拳道？你会跆拳道？
You take karate? You know karate, man?
我不会跆拳道
I don't know karate.
但我会抓狂
But I know crazy.
各位先生女士 现在是红色警戒
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls, this is a Code Red situation.
我们要清空整层楼
We are evacuating the entire floor…
我和我的同事才能…
so that my associate and I…
确保监狱的安全
can secure the prison.
- 你是谁？- 我们是…
- Who are you? - We're special operations, CB…
特别小组
FB-CID.
你们恐怕没听清楚我刚刚说的
Perhaps you didn't hear me when first I spoke…
但你们必须要了解
but it is imperative that you understand…
现在是全面封锁 你们必须到三楼
we're in a complete lockdown situation. We have to get you to the third floor…
抱歉 你说完了吗？
I'm sorry. Were you finished?
他们说你能控制金属
They told me you control metal.
他们？
"They"?
我妈以前也认识一个这样的人
You know, my mom once knew a guy who could do that.
抱歉 我不喜欢使用暴力
I'm sorry, I'm just not very good with violence.
查尔斯？
Charles?
我也很高兴见到你 老友
Good to see you too, old friend.
而且你能走路
And walking.
这我可不想谢谢你
No thanks to you.
我完全没想过还会见到你
You're the last person in the world I expected to see today.
相信我
Believe me…
不到最后关头我也不会来
I wouldn't be here if I didn't have to.
如果我们把你弄出去 你要听我的
If we get you out of here, we do it my way.
不杀人
No killing.
不戴头盔
No helmet.
就算我想也无法反抗你
I couldn't disobey you even if I wanted.
我再也不会进入你的脑袋
I'm never getting inside of that head again.
我需要你保证 艾瑞克
I need your word, Erik.
通通不准动
Nobody move!
不准动
Hold it right there!
- 查尔斯 - 不准动
- Charles. - Don't move.
手举起来 不然我们开枪了
Hands up, or we will shoot!
- 让他们住手 查尔斯 - 我没办法
- Freeze them, Charles. - I can't.
手举起来
Hands up!
不要
No!
谢了 小子
Thanks, kid.
彼得 非常谢谢你
Peter, thank you very, very much.
你好好照顾自己
You take care.
我看到飞行计划了 你们去巴黎干嘛？
I saw your flight plan in the cockpit. Why are you going to Paris?
（和平条约将在巴黎签暑）
要是你的爪是金属的…
Imagine if they were metal.
- 帮我还这辆车 - 好
- Do me a favor and return it for me. - Okay.
还有 彼得
And, Peter?
慢慢来
Take it slow.
他们从哪里找到你的？
Where did they dig you up?
你一定觉得难以相信
You're gonna find this hard to believe…
但派我来的人是你
but you sent me.
你和查尔斯
You and Charles.
从未来派我来
From the future.
你怎么会丧失能力？
How did you lose them?
治疗我脊椎的药影响我的DNA
The treatment for my spine affects my DNA.
你宁愿走路也不要超能力？
You sacrificed your powers so you could walk?
我放弃超能力才睡得着
I sacrificed my powers so that I could sleep.
你又懂什么
What do you know about it?
我也失去了很多
I've lost my fair share.
别哭啊 艾瑞克
Dry your eyes, Erik.
哭也不会让你做的事变成对的
It doesn't justity what you've done.
你根本不知道我做了什么
You have no idea what I've done.
我知道你夺走了我最重要的东西
I know that you took the things that mean the most to me.
也许你应该更努力为他们而战
Maybe you should have fought harder for them.
如果你想开战 艾瑞克
If you want a fight, Erik…
- 坐下 - 我就跟你开战
- Sit down. - I will give you a fight!
让他来
Let him come.
你抛下了我
You abandoned me!
你带走了她
You took her away…
而且抛下了我
and you abandoned me!
精灵
Angel.
魔王
Azazel.
白皇后
Emma.
海妖
Banshee.
那些变种人兄弟姐妹
Mutant brothers and sisters…
全都死了
all dead!
无数的同伴
Countless others…
被抓去做实验
experimented on.
遭受虐待
Butchered!
艾瑞克
Erik!
你在哪里 查尔斯？
Where were you, Charles?
我们应该要保护他们的
We were supposed to protect them!
你的人需要的时候你在哪里？
Where were you when your own people needed you?
躲躲藏藏 你和汉克都是
Hiding! You and Hank!
假装你们是普通人
Pretending to be something you're not!
艾瑞克
Erik!
你抛弃了我们所有人
You abandoned us all.
原来你一直都是混蛋
So, you were always an asshole.
我相信我们在未来是好哥儿们
I take it we're best buddies in the future.
我花了好多年想打倒你
I spent a lot of years trying to bring you down, bub.
你成功了吗？
How does that work out for you?
你很像我
You're like me.
你是生存者
You're a survivor.
你要不要把东西捡起来？
Do you wanna pick all that shit up?
（巴黎）
将军 请少喝一点 明天是大日子
General, maybe you should slow down, we have a big day tomorrow.
这是庆祝我们难得打败万恶的美国
We're celebrating, captain. It's not every day you win a war, let alone against the American devils.
我要再开一瓶
I'm getting another bottle.
抱歉
Excuse me.
绝对是我不好
I'm pretty sure it was my fault.
你会说越南话？
You speak Vietnamese.
我是口译员
I'm an interpreter.
我会说很多种语言
I speak many tongues.
让我再请你喝一杯
Let me buy you another drink…
除非你不是一个人
unless you're here with someone.
我是一个人
I'm alone.
一瓶约翰走路 谢谢
A bottle of Johnnie Walker please.
你明天要去高峰会吗？
You're going to the Summit tomorrow?
关心政治的美女…
A pretty girl interested in politics…
外表是会骗人的
Looks can be deceiving.
女士
Lady.
再让我看一些 宝贝？
Show me more, baby?
脱掉衣服？
Clothes off?
怎么了？你觉得我这样不美吗？
What's the matter, baby? You don't think I look pretty like this?
（您受邀参加巴黎和平奖颁奖典礼）
想玩玩吗？我们很久没玩了
Fancy a game? It's been a while.
我不想下棋 谢谢
I'm not in the mood for games, thank you.
我十年没喝过酒了
I haven't had a real sip in ten years.
我没杀总统
I didn't kill the President.
那颗子弹转弯了 艾瑞克
The bullet curved, Erik.
因为我想救他
Because I was trying to save him.
但他们阻止了我
They took me out before I could.
你为什么想救他？
Why would you try and save him?
因为他跟我们一样
Because he was one of us.
你一定觉得我很傻
You must think me so foolish.
我们总是说他们会追杀我们
We've always said they would come after us.
没想到他们会利用瑞雯的DNA
I never imagined they'd use Raven's DNA to do it.
你上次见到她是什么时候？
When did you last see her?
我去达拉斯那一天
The day I left for Dallas.
她怎么样？
And how was she?
坚强
Strong.
执着
Driven.
忠诚
Loyal.
她还好吗？
How was she?
她…
She was…
我们…
We were…
我能明白为何你如此重视她
I could see why she meant so much to you.
你应该以她为豪 查尔斯
You should be proud of her, Charles.
她为了我们的目标四处奋斗
She's out there fighting for our cause.
是你的目标
Your cause.
我养大的女孩不是杀人狂
The girl I raised was not capable of killing.
你没有养大她 你们一起长大
You didn't raise her, you grew up with her.
她会长大的 所以她才离开
She couldn't stay a little girl forever, that's why she left.
她离开是因为你影响她的内心
She left because you got inside her head.
那不是我的能力
That's not my power.
她做出了选择
She made a choice.
但现在我们知道这项选择的后果了
But now we know where that choice leads, don't we?
她会杀了崔斯克 然后被抓
She's going to murder Trask, they're going to capture her…
然后他们会把我们斩草除根
and then they're going to wipe us out.
只要我们先找到她就不会
Not if we get to her first.
只要我们明天改变历史就不会发生
Not if we change history tomorrow.
抱歉 查尔斯
I'm sorry, Charles…
我对一切感到遗憾
for what happened.
真的
I truly am.
我很久没下棋了
It's been a while since I've played.
我会客气点
I'll go easy on you.
或许是唯一一次公平的竞争
Might finally be a fair fight.
你先下
You have the first move.
世界各国的外交官齐聚皇家饭店
The diplomats from all around the world are arriving here today at the Hotel Royal.
这是历史性的一日
It's an historic day.
美军正式结束介入越战
It's the official ending of the United States' military involvement in Vietnam.
现在来的是南越外交部长
There we have the South Vietnamese Foreign Minister…
还有另一位南越代表
With other South Vietnamese dignitaries.
高峰会还有一小时才开始
The Summit doesn't begin for another hour.
饭店为您和贵宾在楼上安排了房间
The hotel has arranged a private room upstairs for your special guests.
时间很够了
That will be plenty of time.
各位午安 谢谢你们过来
Good afternoon, everyone. Hello, thank you for coming.
恭喜你们的胜利
Congratulations on winning this war.
我知道你们要到楼下握手照相
Now, I know you all have hands to shake and photos to take downstairs…
所以我直接讲重点
so I will get right to the point.
我们现在有新的敌人
There is a new enemy out there.
这个敌人会让你们的军火一无是处
An enemy that will render your arsenals useless…
让军队束手无策
your armies powerless…
让国家毫无抵抗能力
and your nations defenseless.
你们需要新的武器 哨兵机器人
You will need a new weapon for this war I call them Sentineis.
取名自古代守卫城门的哨兵
Named after the ancient guardians that stood at the gates of the citadel.
它们的飞行能力和猎犬喷射机相同
They have the aeronautic capabilities of a Harrier jet.
身上的火力
Armed with guns that can fire off…
每分钟可发射两千多发的热陶瓷弹药
more than 2, 000 rounds per minute ofthermoceramic ammunition.
如果只是尺寸 力量 速度…
But size, power, speed…
洛克希德或波音公司都做得到
you could find that at Lockheed or Boeing.
可是哨兵机器人这么特别
No, what makes the Sentinels so special…
是因为它们能找出变种X基因
is the ability to target the mutant X-gene.
基因导航系统能锁定半里外的目标
A genetic guidance system that can lock onto a mark a half a mile away.
只有确认目标后才会攻击
It won't trigger unless it has identified the target.
这个武器让人类免除不必要的伤亡
With this weapon, there will be no human collateral damage.
如果我在这里打开 系统也不会启动
If I turn it on, the system couldn't even activate in here.
除非这里有变种人
Unless there's a mutant.
这一定有什么问题
There has to be a some kind of mistake.
我的机器不会出问题
My machines don't make mistakes.
你是什么东西？
What are you?
我向你保证…
I assure you…
不要开枪
No, don't shoot it.
我向你保证我不知道你在说什么
I assure you, I don't know what you're talking about.
瑞雯
Raven!
瑞雯 瑞雯
Raven? Raven!
瑞雯？
Raven?
查尔斯？
Charles?
我们来找你了 我和艾瑞克
We've come for you, Erik and I.
一起来的
Together.
我没想过还会见到你
I never thought I'd see you again.
我很久以前就承诺会保护你
I made you a promise a long time ago that I would protect you.
我会保护你的
I'm going to keep you safe.
我们不会让他们抓到你
I'm going to keep you out of their hands.
艾瑞克？
Erik?
艾瑞克 你在干嘛？
Erik? What are you doing?
保护我们的未来
Securing our future.
原谅我 魔形女
Forgive me, Mystique.
只要你活着 我们就不会安全
As long as you're out there, we'll never be safe.
艾瑞克
Erik…
查尔斯 用你的能力阻止他
Use your power, Charles. Stop him.
他做不到
He can't.
他要失控了
He's slipping back.
我快控制不住他了
I'm losing him.
史崔克
Stryker!
会有人接棒完成计划的 金钢狼
Someone will finish what we've started Wolverine!
等着看吧
One day!
抓好他
Restrain him.
艾瑞克
Erik!
我在哪里？
Where am I?
为什么我会在这里？
How the hell did I get here?
什么？是你来找我们的
What? You came to us.
- 你是谁？- 查尔斯
- Who are you? - Charles.
- 查尔斯赛维尔 - 我不认识你
- Charles Xavier! - I don't know you.
他是什么东西？
What the hell is that?
我来处理 你去吧
Look, I can deal with this. Just go.
去阻止艾瑞克
Stop Erik!
- 艾瑞克 求你 - 我很抱歉
- Erik, please… - I'm sorry.
艾瑞克
Erik…
你是罗根 他是汉克 我是查尔斯
You're Logan, that's Hank McCoy, I'm Charles Xavier.
你过去几天都和我们在一起
You spent the last couple of days with us.
你吃了迷幻药
You're on acid.
有人给你品质很差的药
Somebody gave you really bad acid, yeah?
你撑着 我们可以解决的
Just hold on tight, we'll get through this together.
天哪 幻影猫
Oh, my God, Kitty.
她受了很重的伤
She's wounded pretty bad.
我控制住他了
I got him.
教授？
Professor?
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
我看到某个以后会让我受苦的人
I just saw someone who's gonna bring me a lot of pain someday.
瑞雯呢？
Where's Raven?
- 走了 - 什么？
- Gone. - What?
我们得离开这里
We have to get out of here.
我们想知道有没有…
We want to know if there's any sort of connection with…
昨天的巴黎和平高峰会
Yesterday the Paris Peace Summit…
受到不明攻击者袭击
was rocked by the appearance of unidentified assailants…
他们是前所未见的东西
the likes of which the world has never seen.
全国陷入恐慌 民众的疑问是
Mass hysteria has gripped the nation as people ask…
他们从哪里来？他们会回来吗？
"Where did they come from? Will they be back?"
最重要的是 他们是敌是友？
And most importantly, "Are they friend or foe?"
以上是伦敦特派记者托比艾略特
That was London correspondent Toby Elliot…
在昨天的巴黎和平高峰会报导
reporting from the Paris Peace Summit yesterday.
他妈的
Fuck me.
我们的对手到底是什么？私下说
What the hell are we dealing with here? Off the record.
两天前 艾瑞克这个人
Two days ago, this man, Erik Lehnsherr…
从五角大厦戒备最森严的监狱逃脱
escaped from a maximum security prison inside the Pentagon.
我们相信这个女人以前是他的伙伴
We believe that this woman is a former associate of Lehnsherr's.
他们在62年古巴危机时出现在古巴
They were together in Cuba, the day of the crisis in '62.
他也涉入甘迺迪谋杀案
He was also implicated in Kennedy's assassination.
那个东西呢？
What about that thing?
我们不知道那是什么
We don't know what that thing is, sir.
其实我们不知道他们是什么
Actually, we really don't know what any of them are.
知道 我们知道
Yes. Yes, we do.
他们是变种人
They're mutants.
他有控制金属的能力
He has the power to control metal.
据我所知 你们的武器都是金属
Last I checked, that's what most of your weapons were made of.
而她可以变成任何人的模样
And she can transform into anyone.
将军 秘密探员
A general, a secret serviceman.
甚至是您 总统先生
Even you, Mr. President.
只要她想 她就能走进这里
She could walk into this office…
下令展开核弹攻击
and order a nuclear strike if she was in the mood.
光他们两个就这么强了
And that's only two of them.
我们有对策吗？能抵抗他们吗？
Do we have any countermeasures? Any defense?
我就在等你这么问我
I was waiting for you to ask me that question.
这是一项秘密实验计划
That's an experimental program, sir. Strictly off the books.
你是说世界上有这些变种人
You're telling me these mutants are out in the world…
而我们只能靠这些金属巨人？
and our best defense are these giant metal robots?
很多变种人的外表都和我们一样
Many of the mutants look like us.
我的哨兵可以分辨差异
My Sentinels can tell the difference.
我有八个原型可以随时启动
I have eight prototypes ready to go.
它们是最先进的聚合物 完全无金属
They're built out of a space-age polymer, not an ounce of metal on them.
我要你示范看看
I want to make a demonstration.
我要全世界知道我们能保护他们
I want the world to know that we can protect them.
你需要多少钱才能开始运作？
What do you need to get these things operational?
我已经把数字交给国会了
I already gave that number to Congress.
可惜他们拒绝通过
Unfortunately, they elected to shut me down.
要重新启动需要更大一笔钱
It's going to cost a bit more to turn them on.
- 你尽管开口 - 还有一件事
- Whatever you need. - And one more thing.
如果我们真的抓到他们 我要她
If we do manage to capture them, I would like her.
当然是为了研究
For research purposes, of course.
我不管你要谁 只要不是我就好
I don't care who you screw, as long as it's not me.
真是可怕
Terrible thing.
什么可怕？
What is?
天生就长那样真可怕
Being born like that.
是吗？
Is it?
你能想像…
Can you imagine…
在镜子里看见这东西回望你吗？
Looking in the mirror and seeing that staring back at you?
我可以
Yes, I can.
你想她是从哪里来的？
Where do you think she comes from?
她有家人吗？
You think she has a family?
是的
Yes.
她有的
She does.
如果你想搞鬼 我会刺穿你的喉咙
If I see so much as a screw move, I will jam this into your throat.
你怎么找到我的？
How did you find me?
你教得好
You taught me well.
我们很久没这么靠近了
It's been a long time since we were this close.
我很想你
I missed you.
你想杀了我
You tried to kill me.
这样才能救剩下的人
So the rest of us could live.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我们得到未来的消息
We received a message from the future.
少骗我了
Don't lie to me.
我从来没骗你 永远也不会
I never have, and I never will.
你的血和基因会被做成武器消灭我们
Humans use your blood, your genes, to create a weapon that wipes us all out.
我只是为了保护我们的未来
I was only doing what I thought necessary to secure our future.
那我何不为了我的未来杀了你？
So what's to stop me from killing you right now and securing my future?
没错
Nothing.
反正已经不重要了
It doesn't matter anymore.
他们从你留下的血迹得到DNA了
They have your DNA. Your blood was on the street.
那又要怪谁？
Whose fault was that?
怪我
Mine.
我知道他们已经在做武器了
I've seen their plans. They're creating a weapon.
现在他们可以再进一步发展
And now they have what they need to take it further.
我们得趁还占上风时开战
We have to strike now, while we still hold the upper hand.
我已经看过够多朋友死去了
I've seen too many friends die, Erik.
我不想开战 只想找凶手复仇
I don't want a war. I only want the man who murdered them.
这是战争
This is war.
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
我不在的时候你迷失了吗？
Did you lose your way while I was gone?
你还是查尔斯的瑞雯吗？
Are you still Charles' Raven?
还是魔形女？
Or are you Mystique?
我的敌人是崔斯克
Trask is the enemy.
杀一个人是不够的
Killing one man isn't enough.
对你来说永远不够
It never was for you.
再见 艾瑞克
Goodbye, Erik.
怎么了？
What happened?
- 来吧 - 他能走路吗？
- Come on. - Can he walk?
他需要他的药
He needs his treatment.
- 我又听见了 - 我知道 没关系
- I can hear them. - I know. It's okay.
- 别让我再听见了 - 我去拿药
- Can you make it stop? - I'll get them.
听着
Hey, hey.
振作一点
Pull yourself together.
计划还没有结束
It's not over yet.
你根本不相信
You don't believe that.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
我的腿不能动
As these go…
能力就回来了
this comes back.
全部都回来了
They all come back.
听着
Look.
我还在这里
I'm still here…
她还在外面
and she's still out there.
我们需要你帮忙 查尔斯
We need your help, Charles.
不是这样的你 原来的你
Not like this. I need you.
没有你的能力我们就找不到瑞雯
We can't find Raven. Not without your powers.
我加重了剂量 因为你少打一次
I added a little extra because you missed a dose.
查尔斯
Charles.
汉克 帮我个忙
Hank, do me a favor.
可以带我到书房吗 拜讬？
Would you help me to my study, please?
来吧 我撑着你
Come on, I got you.
你确定吗？
Are you sure about this?
完全不确定
Absolutely not.
这个生物很特别
This creature is extraordinary.
她的基因是变种的关键
Her genes could hold the key to mutation itself.
我需要更多
I need more.
我们从巴黎人行道只能弄到这些
That's all they were able to scrape off the pavement in Paris.
血液还不够
More than blood.
我需要脑部组织
I need brain tissue…
脊髓液 骨髓
spinal fluid, bone marrow.
想想看…
Imagine…
我们会有能配合目标变形的哨兵
Sentinels that could transform, adapt to any target.
要是能抓到她就好了
If I could just get my hands on her.
这个女孩能让计划有大幅进展
This girl could leap the program forward years…
前进数十年
decades into the future.
你儿子现在多大 少校？
How old is your son now, Major?
杰森吗？
Jason?
快10岁了 真不敢相信
He's coming up on ten now, if you can believe it.
还有八年就能从军
Eight years from fighting age.
我们已经用尸袋装了多少男儿回来？
And how many of our sons and brothers did we just ship home in body bags?
五万 五万五千？
Maybe fifty, fifty-five thousand?
敌人那边呢？
And how many more on the other side?
人类有历史以来
Never before…
我们将第一次
in all of human history…
因为有共同目标而团结一心
has there been a cause which could unite us as a species.
就是现在
Until now.
你真的很恨变种人吧？
You really hate mutants, don't you?
正好相反 我很仰慕他们
On the contrary, I rather admire them.
他们有那些能力
The things they can do.
我认为变种人是我们的救赎
I see mutants as our salvation.
是共同的敌人
A common enemy.
我们会携手对抗终极大敌
A common struggle against the ultimate enemy.
大灭绝
Extinction.
我相信我们的新朋友
I believe our new friends…
会帮助我们进入新的纪元
are going to help us usher in a new era, Bill.
一个有长久的…
A new era of genuine…
真正的和平的纪元
and long-lasting peace.
注意 运输两小时后开始
Attention, attention. Transport departure in two hours.
重复 运输两小时后开始
Repeat. Transport departure in two hours.
你上次来这里是什么时候？
When was the last time you were down here?
我们最后一次找学生的时候
The last time we went looking for students.
像是上辈子的事了
A lifetime ago.
欢迎你 教授
Welcome, Professor
瑞雯受伤了 她动作不快
Raven's wounded. She won't be moving fast.
我很久没用这些肌肉了
These are muscles I haven't stretched in a long time.
查尔斯
Charles!
查尔斯 没事的
Charles? It's all right.
我去检查发电机
I'll go check the generator.
不是机器的关系吧？
It's not the machinery, is it?
我做不到 我的脑…
I can't do this. My mind…
你可以的
Yes, you can.
- 我撑不住 - 你只是生疏了
- It won't take it. - You're just a little rusty.
你不明白 这不是生疏的问题
You don't understand. It's not a question of being rusty.
我能开开关 转门把
I can flip the switches. I can turn the knobs.
但我的力量来自这里 来自…
But my power comes from here. It comes from…
但已经坏了
And it's broken.
我觉得自己像学生一样
I feel like one of my students.
感到无助
Helpless.
来这里是个错误
It was a mistake coming down here.
救出艾瑞克是个错误
It was a mistake freeing Erik.
整件事都是该死的错误
This whole thing has been one bloody mistake.
抱歉 罗根 但他们搞错人了
I'm sorry, Logan, but they sent back the wrong man.
你说对了
You're right.
我是错的人
I am.
他们本来要送你回来
Actually, it was supposed to be you.
但只有我的身体撑得住
But I was the only one who could physically make the trip.
我不知道我来多久了
And I don't know how long I've got here.
但我知道很久以前
But I do know that a long time ago…
其实是从现在开始的很久以后
actually, a long time from now…
我是你最无助的学生
I was your most helpless student.
但你释放了我的心灵
And you unlocked my mind.
你让我知道我的能力
You showed me what I was.
让我知道我能成就什么
You showed me what I could be.
我不知道怎么帮你
I don't know how to do that for you.
你是对的 我不能
You're right. I don't.
但是我知道谁能帮你
But I know someone who might.
读我的心
Look into my mind.
你看到增幅器的下场了 别让我读心
You saw what I did to Cerebro. You don't want me inside your head.
你没有新把戏…
There's no damage you can do…
能再伤害我了 相信我
that hasn't already been done. Trust me.
来吧
Come on.
你醒了
Hey.
嘿 罗根
Hey, Logan.
嗨 琴
Hi, Jean.
杀了我
Kill me.
我爱你
I love you.
你真可怜
You poor, poor man.
看透我
Look past me.
我不要你承受的苦难
No, I don't want your suffering.
我不要你的未来
I don't want your future!
看穿我的未来
Look past my future.
看看你的未来
Look for your future.
就是这样
That's it.
查尔斯
Charles.
所以我们的未来是这样
So this is what becomes of us.
艾瑞克是对的
Erik was right.
人类会这么对我们
Humanity does this to us.
所以我们要让他们看到更好的路
Not if we show them a better path.
你还相信吗？
You still believe?
只是犯过一次错
Just because someone stumbles, loses their way…
不代表永远不能回头
it doesn't mean they're lost forever.
有时候我们需要一点帮忙
Sometimes we all need a little help.
我不是过去的我了
I'm not the man I was.
我一旦开始使用能力
I open my mind…
自己就无法招架
and it almost overwhelms me.
你害怕 增幅器也知道
You're afraid, and Cerebro knows it.
这些声音
All those voices…
这些痛苦
so much pain.
你怕的不是他们的痛苦
It's not their pain you're afraid of.
是你自己的痛苦
It's yours, Charles.
虽然这样很可怕
And as frightening as it may be…
但痛苦会让你更强
that pain will make you stronger.
如果你让自己去感受
If you allow yourself to feel it…
拥抱恐惧
embrace it…
你会比自己想像得更强
it will make you more powertul than you ever imagined.
这是我们最棒的天赋
It's the greatest gift we have…
能承受他们的痛苦但不会崩溃
to bear their pain without breaking.
而且这股力量的源头
And it's born…
是最具人性的力量
from the most human power.
就是希望
Hope.
拜讬你 查尔斯
Please, Charles…
我们需要你重拾希望
we need you to hope again.
找到你要的东西了吗？
Find what you were looking for?
电力恢复了
The power's back on.
是的
Yes.
的确是
Yes, it is.
她失血太多了
She's lost too much blood.
她不能这样下去
She can't keep going like this.
我们别无选择 冰人
We have no choice, Bobby.
- 我们能让他醒来 - 不行
- We can wake him up. - No!
他们需要更多时间
They need more time.
我…
I had…
我看到了过去
a glimpse into the past.
如果我们现在叫醒罗根
If we wake Logan now…
我们可能会让自己的命运更悲惨
we may set our fate on an even darker course.
他们需要更多时间
They need more time.
还有其他人
There is someone else.
不 没有人有幻影猫的能力
No, no one has Kitty's power.
有人可以取走她的能力 取代她
Someone that could take her power, take her place.
她也对你做过
She took yours once.
小淘气
Rogue.
抱歉 冰人 她一定死了
I'm sorry, Bobby, she must be dead.
我好多年都无法联系上她
I haven't been able to make a connection with her for years.
那是因为他们把她安置在 你的能力无法从外面
That's because they're keeping her in the one place your mind can't reach
联系的地方
from the outside.
她在脑波增幅器中
She's in Cerebro.
教授 她在你的房子中
She's in your house, Professor.
他们对她做实验
They're experimenting on her.
试着进入她的能力 所以他们能夺取我们的
Trying to tap into her power, so they can take ours.
我们所有人的
Take all of ours.
如果你知道这个 为什么没有找她？
If you knew this, why didn't you go after her?
我们试过了 但戒备太森严
We tried. It's too heavily guarded.
我知道几件这房子的事 他们并不知情
I may know a few things about that house they don't.
幻影猫 我去找帮手
Kitty, I'm going to get help.
我会带人回来帮你
I'm gonna bring back somebody to help you.
请安全地归来
Please, just bring yourself back.
瑞雯 停下来
Raven, stop.
别跑了
Stop running.
查尔斯？
Charles?
你在哪里？
Where are you?
我在家里
Back at the house…
你归属的地方
where you should be.
我要你回家来
I need you to come home.
我知道该怎么做
I know what I need to do.
如果你杀了崔斯克
If you kill Trask…
就会让数不清的人变得跟他一样
you will be creating countless more just like him.
然后我也会杀了他们
Then I'll kill them, too.
那是艾瑞克的想法 不是你的
Those are Erik's words, not yours.
跟我一起长大的那女孩不会杀人
The girl I grew up with wasn't capable of killing.
她很善良
She was good…
美好 充满同情心
fair, full of compassion.
我有同情心
I have compassion.
只是对崔斯克没有
Just not for Trask.
他杀了我们太多同伴
He's murdered too many of us.
阻止她 控制她的想法
Shut her down, Charles. Get in her head.
她不让我进去
She's not letting me in.
我撑得很辛苦 我还不够强
I'm barely holding on. I'm not strong enough yet.
我知道崔斯克做了什么
I know what Trask has done…
但杀了他也不能让大家复活
but killing him will not bring them back.
反而会让你…
It will set you on a path…
走上无法回头的路
from which there is no return.
开始无止尽的杀戮
An endless cycle of killing.
最后我们会和他们同归于尽
Us and them, until there is nothing left.
但我和你现在就能阻止这件事
But we can stop it, right now, you and I.
但你必须先回家
You just have to come home.
我必须？
I have to?
你一点都没变 查尔斯
You haven't changed at all, Charles.
我说过了
Like I said…
我知道我必须做什么
I know exactly what I have to do.
你知道？
You do?
不管你去哪里 我都会找到你的
Then, wherever you go, I will find you.
瑞雯 如果你强迫我 我会阻止你
And, Raven, if you make me, I will stop you.
祝好运 查尔斯
Good luck, Charles.
她在哪里？
Where is she?
她在机场 她在机场准备登机 任何地方她都有可能去
She's in an airport, boarding a plane. She could be going anywhere.
查尔斯 休息一下
Get some rest, Charles.
我们早上再追踪她 看看她到底去了哪里
We'll track her in the morning and find out exactly where she's going.
火箭降落在基地外围
rockets did land outside the base,
造成5位平民死亡 12位受伤
killing five civilians and wounding 12 others.
有事？
Yeah?
你知道那些东西会让你离患癌症吗？
You know that those things can give you cancer?
我在实验室做过一些毒物检验
I've done some toxicology tests in the lab, and…
你想要什么吗？
You want something?
好 我
Yeah, I'm…
我知道这很复杂
I know it's complicated,
关于你可不可说的事情 可能有不同的规定和理由
and there's probably all kinds of rules and reasons for what you can and can't say,
但我想你可否告诉我
but I was wondering if you could tell me
在未来 我有没有成功？
in the future, do I make it?
没有
No.
好
Okay.
没关系 谢谢
It's okay. Thanks.
嘿 孩子？
Hey, kid?
只有我来的世界
It's just the world I came from.
我们是要回到过去
We're going backwards in time.
总统明天将在白宫前演说
Tomorrow, in front of the White House, the President will make his announcement.
由国防部长莱德陪同
He will be joined by Secretary of Defense Laird…
他们甚至向著名科学家崔斯克求助
and has even sought the help of renowned scientist Bolivar Trask…
他是变种人问题的特别顾问
his special advisor to combat this mutant issue.
白宫有三个现场直播网路
The White House has all three networks to air the event live,
因为这不只对美国来说很重要
as it is a matter of importance not only to the United States,
对全世界的每个公民都很重要
but to every citizen from around the globe.
没有其他关于这事件的细节
There are no other details about the event…
瑞雯
Raven…
天啊
My God.
我不知道你在这里做什么？
I don't understand. What are you doing here?
我…
I…
我没地方去
I guess, I just realized I have nowhere else to go.
- 我要叫醒查尔斯 - 不行
- I've gotta wake Charles… - No, don't.
等等
Just wait.
你现在这样不应该走路的
You really shouldn't walk on this.
我遇过更糟的
I've had worse.
你这些年都住在这里？
So, you've been living here all these years?
总要有人要照顾查尔斯
Someone had to take care of Charles.
你知道 他很想你
You know, he's missed you.
他想念的是以前的我
He misses who I was.
我已经不是他想要的人了
I'm not who he wants me to be anymore.
我想你
I've missed you.
所以你一直像这样
So, you're like this all the time now.
像怎样？
Like what?
这样
This.
不全然是
No, not all the time.
我早上打一针 如果我醒来就需要另一针
I take a shot in the morning, and I need another if I get worked up.
- 醒来 - 对 当我
- Worked up? - Yeah, yeah, when I'm…
情绪化或是兴奋
emotional or excited.
任何动物的欲望
Any animal urges.
通常我是可以抵抗的
Usually, I can fight them off.
或许我们不该抵抗 自然而然发生在我们身上的事情
Well, maybe, we shouldn't have to fight off the things that come naturally to us.
记得你最后跟我说的话吗？
Do you remember one of the last things you said to me?
长这样 永远不会被认为是美丽的？
That I would never be deemed beautiful, looking like this?
你还是这样认为？
Do you still think that?
或许吧 看到发生在巴黎的事情
Maybe. You saw what happened in Paris.
你知道他们怎么看待我们的
You know what they think of us.
你认为呢？
What do you think?
我觉得你很美
I think you're beautiful.
你自己呢？
What about yourself?
你该休息一下
You should get some rest.
很高兴你回来了
I'm glad you're home.
汉克？
Hank?
记得我跟你说过 最后的一件事？
Do you remember the last thing I said to you?
这是变种与骄傲
It was, "Mutant and proud."
旧瓦斯管道和水管 直接连到了这房子
The old gas and waterpipes lead straight to the house.
墙是由钢筋建构的
The walls are made of reinforced steel.
换句话说 是门
In other words, a door.
你直接走在大厅了
You're walking directly over the hall now.
我一直在那厚板上 让我告诉你那是什么感觉
I've been on that slab. Let me show you how it feels.
小淘气 小淘气 快点醒来
Rogue, Rogue, come on. Wake up.
小淘气
Rogue.
快点 小淘气 快醒来 快醒来 是我
Come on, Rogue, wake up. Wake up, it's me.
不
No.
小淘气 小淘气 没事 他跟我一起的
Rogue, Rogue, Rogue, it's okay. He's with me.
我们要救你出去
We're gonna get you out of here.
艾瑞克 冰人
Erik, Bobby.
快离开那里 马上
Get out of there! Now!
带着她
Take her!
冰人 不
Bobby! No!
冰人
Bobby!
教授
Professor!
救我们出去
Get us out of here.
- 冰人 - 我知道
- Bobby. - I know.
很抱歉 查尔斯
I'm sorry, Charles.
冰人在哪？
Where's Bobby?
抱歉 幻影猫
I'm sorry, Kitty.
你好 罗根
Hello, Logan.
小淘气
Rogue.
瑞雯之前在这里
Raven was here.
- 我搞砸了 - 糟糕
- I screwed up. - Shit.
现在追踪不到她
We can't track her now.
她剪掉她的联系
She's cut her ties.
我昨晚有看到新闻
Hey, I saw in the news last night
今天下午华盛顿会有关于
there's going to be an announcement in Washington this afternoon
变种人协定的声明
about a new protocol for mutants.
我设定了一个系统
I set the system I designed…
记录三家电视台报导的巴黎新闻
to record any news about Paris over all three networks…
还有公共电视
and PBS.
才三家 真厉害
All three? Wow.
对 还有公共电视
Yeah, and PBS.
看我找到什么了？
Look what I found.
总统明天将在白宫前演说
Tomorrow, in front of the White House, the President will make his announcement.
由国防部长莱德陪同
He will be joined by Secretary of Defense Laird…
他们甚至向著名科学家崔斯克求助
and has even sought the help of renowned scientist Bolivar Trask…
他是变种人问题的特别顾问
his special advisor to combat this mutant issue.
白宫要求…
The White House has asked…
瑞雯不明白
Raven doesn't realize…
如果她在这种场合杀了崔斯克
that if she kills Trask at an event like that…
全世界都会看到
with the whole world watching…
那我大老远来就没用了
Then I came a long way for nothing.
还有个坏消息 我看新闻说
And there's more bad news. I saw in a report…
他们在巴黎发现她的血迹
they found traces of her blood in Paris.
所以他们已经有了她的DNA
For all we know, they already have her DNA…
他们就要这东西
which is all they'd need.
用来制造未来的哨兵机器人
To create the Sentinels of the future.
量子物理中有一个理论
There's a theory in quantum physics…
时间是永远不变的
that time is immutable.
就像一条河 你丢石头进去
It's like a river. You can throw a pebble into it…
会有涟漪 但流向不会改变
and create a ripple, but the current always corrects itself.
不管你做什么 河的流向永远不变
No matter what you do, the river just keeps flowing in the same direction.
你想说什么？
What are you trying to say?
我的意思是
What I'm saying is…
如果战争是无法避免的呢？
what if the war is inevitable?
如果她就是会杀了崔斯克呢？
What if she's meant to kill Trask?
如果她就是这样的人呢？
What if this is just simply who she is?
只因为犯过一次错
Just because someone stumbles, loses their way…
并不表示永远不能回头
doesn't mean they're lost forever.
我不相信那个理论 汉克
No, I don't believe that theory, Hank.
我不相信她是那种人
And I cannot believe that is who she is.
准备飞机
Ready the plane.
我们要去华盛顿
We're going to Washington.
你还好吗？
You all right?
渐入佳境
Getting there.
不管今天怎么样 我都要你答应我
Whatever happens today, I need you to promise me something.
你已经从我这里看到很多坏事
You've looked into my mind and seen a lot of bad…
但你也看到一些好事
but you've seen the good, too.
X战警
The X-Men.
答应我你会找到我们
Promise me you'll find us.
用你的能力让我们团结一致
Use your power, bring us together.
引导我们 带领我们
Guide us. Lead us.
暴风女 史考特
Storm. Scott.
琴
Jean.
记住这些名字
Remember those names.
我们有很多人
There are so many of us.
我们需要你 教授
We will need you, Professor.
我会尽力的
I'll do my best.
你尽力就够了
Your best is enough.
相信我
Trust me.
有12架母船要过来 距离10里
There's 12 carriers inbound, 10 miles!
他们找到我们了
They've found us.
来自世界各地成千上万的人
Thousands of people will be gathered here today.
今天一起聚集在这里
They've come from all over the world…
和民众一起见证历史的
to witness history, along with news crews…
还有至少50国的媒体
from at least 50 different countries.
谢谢你
Thank you.
请出示邀请函
Can I see your invitations, please?
是的 可以
Yes, you may.
他们两个是和我一起的
These two are with me.
进去吧
Go ahead.
谢谢
Thank you.
罗根
Logan!
先生 请走这里
Please, this way, sir.
第四步兵团 遭到地雷攻击
Fourth infantry… Took a Bouncing Betty.
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
误伤
Friendly fire.
最糟的哪种
The worst kind.
对
Yeah.
还没找到 但她一定在这里
I haven't found her yet, but she has to be here.
欢迎美国总统
The President of the United States.
各位同胞
My fellow Americans…
今天我们面临史上最严重的威胁
today we face the gravest threat in our history…
变种人
mutants.
面对这个威胁 我们已经做好准备
We have prepared for this threat.
就像奥本海默博士的不朽名言
In the immortal words of Robert Oppenheimer…
看吧
"Behold.
世界从此改变了
"The world will never be the same again."
需要帮忙吗？
Can I help you?
你帮不上忙
No, you can't.
他们来了
Here they come.
这是为了你们 我的兄弟姐妹
This is for you, brothers and sisters.
瑞雯？
Raven?
我找到她了
I have her.
让我走 查尔斯
Let me go, Charles.
在那里 你看到了吗？
There. You see?
秘密干员
Secret Serviceman.
舞台左侧
Left of the stage.
- 我看到了 - 过去
- Got him. - Go.
你在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
我没叫你启动哨兵
I didn't tell you to activate them.
我没有
I didn't.
瑞雯 拜讬你听我说
Raven, please, Ilsten to me.
我们都有第二次机会证明自己
We've been given a second chance to define who we are.
不要这么做
Don't do this.
这里禁止进入
Gentlemen, you cannot pass this point.
你阻止不了那么多哨兵
We can't stop that many.
对 但我们能拖延它们
No, but we can slow them down.
艾瑞克
Erik!
暴风女
Storm!
快走
Go, go, go!
进入第三级警戒
Take us to DEFCON 3.
总统先生 现在是红色警戒
Mr. President, we are Code Red.
空中防御呢？
What's our air defense readiness?
所有的空军都准备好了
All our air defenses are ready one.
这到底怎么回事？
What the hell happened out there?
我会处理的
I will fix it.
你之前也这样说
You said that before.
我本来要展现能力
I wanted to make a statement.
现在全世界都知道我们保护不了他们
Now the whole goddamn world knows we can't protect them.
我会处理的
I will fix it.
你他妈的最好可以
You damn well better.
查尔斯
Charles!
大家都没事吗？
Is everybody okay?
不要
No!
小心后面
Behind you.
发挥你的功能
Do what you were made for.
（变种人）
你在哪里？
Where are you?
交给我 你快走
I got this! Go!
天哪 不要
Oh, dear God, no.
生存者也就只有这么点能耐
So much for being a survivor.
有一个变种人在这里
One of them is in here.
不要 不能杀它
No, no, no! Don't kill it!
我要活捉
I need it alive.
到底是怎么回事？
What the hell has happened?
你们制造这些武器来消灭我们
You built these weapons to destroy us.
为什么？
Why?
因为害怕我们的能力
Because you are afraid of our gifts.
因为我们不一样
Because we are different.
人类总是害怕不同的东西
Humanity has always feared that which is different.
但我要来告诉你
Well, I am here to tell you…
告诉全世界
to tell the world…
你们确实应该要怕我们
you are right to fear us.
我们就是未来
We are the future.
我们会继承这颗星球
We are the ones who will inherit this earth.
任何阻挠我们的人
And anyone who stands in our way…
下场都会和你们眼前的…
will suffer the same fate as these men…
这些人一样
you see before you.
今天你们本来想展示你们的能力
Today was meant to be a display ofyourpower
但我却让你们看见
Instead I give you a glimpse…
我们能对你们造成的强大灾难
of the devastation my race can unleash upon yours.
全世界听好了
Let this be a warning to the world.
我的变种人兄弟姐妹听好了
And to my mutant brothers and sisters out there…
听我说
I say this.
不要再躲藏了
No more hiding.
不用再受苦了
No more suffering.
你们一直生活在阴影中
You have lived in the shadows…
你们羞耻与害怕够久了 出来吧
in shame and fear for too long. Come out.
和我一起
Join me.
一起为了我们团结奋斗
Fight together in a brotherhood of our kind.
崭新的明天
A new tomorrow…
就从今天开始
that starts today.
我和你浪费了那么多年
AIl those years wasted…
彼此对抗 查尔斯
fighting each other, Charles.
让重要的几个人回来…
To have a precious few of them back…
- 总统先生 - 退下
- Mr. President, sir. - Stand down.
我说退下
I said, stand down!
你想展现力量吗？
You want to make a statement?
杀了我 没关系
Kill me. Fine.
但是放过大家
But spare everyone else.
真是勇敢 总统先生
Very heroic, Mr. President…
但你却不打算…
but you had no intention…
放过我们
of sparing any of us.
变种人的未来从今天开始
The future of our species begins now.
（变种人）
你以前比较准
You used to be a better shot.
相信我 我还是很准
Trust me, I still am.
不要干扰我 查尔斯
Get out of my head, Charles!
瑞雯
Raven.
拜讬别让我们从此与人类为敌
Please, do not make us the enemy today.
你看看四周 我们早就是了
Look around you. We already are.
并不是所有人
Not all of us.
你目前为止做的
All you've done so far…
就是救了这些人
is save the lives of these men.
你能让他们看到更好的方向
You can show them a better path.
阻止她 查尔斯
Shut her down, Charles.
从我们认识那天我就想控制你
I've been trying to control you ever since the day we met…
结果却是这样
and look where that's got us.
接下来的发展
Everything that happens now…
都取决于你的决定
is in your hands.
我对你有信心 瑞雯
I have faith in you, Raven.
他交给你了 查尔斯
He's all yours, Charles.
如果让他们抓走我 那我就死定了
If you let them have me, I'm as good as dead.
你知道的
You know that.
我知道
I know.
再见 老朋友
Goodbye, old friend.
再见 艾瑞克
Goodbye, Erik.
你真的要让他们走？
Are you sure you should let them go?
对
Yes.
我对他们抱持希望
I have hope for them.
总有一天我们会重聚 汉克
There's going to be a time, Hank, when we are all together.
那罗根呢？
What about Logan?
（黄金年代经典老歌）
巴克敏斯特富勒是建筑师模范
Buckminster Fuller is a great example of an architect…
他的理想非常乌托邦
whose ideas were very similar to those of a utopian future.
早安 罗根 你今天比较晚
Good morning, Logan. Late start.
祝午餐愉快
Have a good lunch.
很好
Good job.
做得非常好
Very good job.
暴风女
Storm.
琴
Jean.
嗨 罗根
Hey, Logan.
琴
Jean.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
你在这里
You're here.
不然我要在哪里？
Where else would I be?
住手
Whoa.
别乱来 老兄
Easy, pal.
有些事还是不会变
Well, some things never change.
看到你真好 史考特
It's good to see you, Scott.
最好是
Uh-huh.
待会儿见 琴
See you later, Jean.
教授
Professor.
罗根 没事吧？
Logan, is everything all right?
没事
Yeah.
我想应该没事
Yeah, I think it is.
你成功了
You did it.
成功什么？
Did what?
罗根 你没有课要上吗？
Logan, don't you have a class to teach?
我要教书？
A class to teach?
历史课
History.
历史课？
History?
我想我应该需要帮忙
Actually, I could use some help with that.
帮忙什么？
Help with what?
基本上从1973年以后都需要
Pretty much everything after 1973.
我想我知道的历史有点不一样
I think the history I know is a little different.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
很高兴见到你 查尔斯
It's good to see you, Charles.
很高兴见到大家
It's good to see everyone.
因为…
Well…
我得遵守诺言
I had a promise to keep.
我们得好好叙旧一下
You and I have a lot of catching up to do.
是啊
Yeah.
你记得的最后一件事是什么？
What's the last thing you remember?
溺水
Drowning.
过去
The past.
一个新的
A new…
不确定的世界
and uncertain world.
充满无限可能的世界
A world of endless possibilities.
（变种人拯救总统与国会哨兵计划取消）
（崔斯克因出卖国防机密遭逮捕）
有无限的结
And infinite outcomes.
你开玩笑吧
You kidding me?
他还活着
He's alive!
无数的选择决定了我们的命运
Countless choices define our fate.
每一个选择 每一刻
Each choice, each moment…
都时间之河里的每个涟漪
a ripple in the river of time.
史崔克少校 我们要怎么处置他？
What do you want us to do with him, Major Stryker?
当涟漪够多时
Enough ripples…
就能改变潮流
and you change the tide.
把他交给我吧
I'll take him from here.
因为未来永远不只一个
For the future is never truly set.